ANGUS DICKY LI

510 - 629 King Street West, Toronto, ON M5V 0G9, Canada

Mobile: + 1(437) 366-6921 Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dickyli338

Email: angus.dicky.li@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/lad338 Website: https://lad338.github.io

Summary

A responsible, fast-learning **Software Developer** with over 5 years of experience in development. Able to develop and maintain reliable backends in different languages and frameworks. Willing to master skills and pursue new technologies. Possessing required interpersonal communication and collaboration skills. Currently in a career break for migration to Canada. Willing to relocate for Canada opportunities.

Education

The University of Hong Kong

Bachelor of Engineering, Majoring in Computer Science

2014-2018

Final year project

Al Tutor for Programming Class (the Auto Grading Engine)

- A web based auto grading system on code submission of programming learners
- Other than pass or fail, the grading system can also provide recommendations based on big data of pass submission from other students
- Selected components:
 - Extracting abstract syntax tree (AST) in Python program submissions
 - Determining logic flow information from ASTs such as conditional statements and loops
 - Running cluster analysis on big data of AST from programs using R

Work Experience

Crypto.com

Software Developer Hong Kong (remote) Jun 2021 - Jan 2023

- Crypto wallet and exchange
- Worked in User Core team with a team size of 5-7 running in an agile environment
- Maintained user authentication and authorization APIs of over 70 million users
- Implemented anti-spam mechanism using Google Recaptcha and rate limit handling using Redis
- Developed an authentication and authorization microservice using Golang that acted as a source of truth for user identities across different platforms in the Crypto.com ecosystem
- Designed the database schema of the auth microservice in CockroachDB for its scaling in multiple geolocation and Postgres compatibility
- Developed a backup login service for Crypto.com Exchange in Ruby on Rails for server downtime

Software Developer

Hong Kong (remote)

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

- DeFi applications on Cronos chain
- Worked in CronosID, a DeFi name service in the Cronos chain
- Worked on metadata service and subgraph in TypeScript with Node.js
- Worked in DeFi exchange team to develop price candle chart APIs in Go with expected of thousands of requests per second
- Developed CI/CD pipelines for unit test and deployment using CircleCI

Green Tomato

Backend Developer Hong Kong Oct 2018 - May 2021

- Mobile application solutions and consultancy
- Developed backend servers to deliver RESTful APIs for mobile applications using Java/Kotlin with Spring Boot or TypeScript with Node is with clients of restaurant, shopping malls and retails
- Integrated with third party services including CRM and payment services upon client requests
- Shipping backend services in Docker container and running on k8s environments
- Designed and deployed backend services on cloud services such as AWS and GCP
- Prepared API documentation for frontend applications and third parties to integrate
- Promoted to senior backend developer in Jan 2021
- Mentored less experienced developers on code review and onboarding

Skills

- Programing languages: Java, TypeScript, Go, JavaScript, Ruby, Python, Kotlin, Solidity
- **Backend:** Spring Boot, express.js, OpenAPI, REST APIs, GraphQL, Ruby on Rails, RabbitMQ, microservices, OAuth, docker, kubernetes, Strapi CMS
- Frontend: React.js, redux, indexedDB, HTML, CSS
- Cloud: Amazon ELB, Amazon ECS, Amazon ECR, Amazon S3, Google Recaptcha
- Storage: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, CockroachDB, SQL databases, noSQL databases
- Software development lifecycle: Git, CircleCl, agile, JIRA, Confluence, unit tests, postman (newman)
- Other programming skills: Object-oriented programming (OOP), functional programming

Others

Extracurricular

- Programming: Game development in Unity with C#
- Sports: Field Hockey, Volleyball

Languages

- English (fluent)
- Cantonese (native)
- Mandarin (fluent)